<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-GB">
  <!--[if IEMobile 7 ]><html class="no-js iem7" manifest="default.appcache?v=1"><![endif]--> 
<!--[if lt IE 7 ]><html class="no-js ie6" lang="en"><![endif]--> 
<!--[if IE 7 ]><html class="no-js ie7" lang="en"><![endif]--> 
<!--[if IE 8 ]><html class="no-js ie8" lang="en"><![endif]--> 
<!--[if (gte IE 9)|(gt IEMobile 7)|!(IEMobile)|!(IE)]><!--><html class="no-js" lang="en"><!--<![endif]-->
<head>
    <meta charset="utf-8">
    <meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="IE=edge">
    <title>Antonio Fullone</title>
	<meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1, minimum-scale=1">
	<meta name="description" content="Antonio Fullone. Life, food, travelling and coding.">
	<link rel="canonical" href="http://antoniofullone.com/feed.xml">
	<link rel="shortcut icon" href="/img/favicon.ico"/>
	<!-- Custom CSS -->
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/style.css">
	<!--	<script src="/js/modernizr.custom.js"></script> -->
	<script>
	  (function(d) {
	    var config = {
	      kitId: 'szm0avi',
	      scriptTimeout: 3000
	    },
	    h=d.documentElement,t=setTimeout(function(){h.className=h.className.replace(/\bwf-loading\b/g,"")+" wf-inactive";},config.scriptTimeout),tk=d.createElement("script"),f=false,s=d.getElementsByTagName("script")[0],a;h.className+=" wf-loading";tk.src='//use.typekit.net/'+config.kitId+'.js';tk.async=true;tk.onload=tk.onreadystatechange=function(){a=this.readyState;if(f||a&&a!="complete"&&a!="loaded")return;f=true;clearTimeout(t);try{Typekit.load(config)}catch(e){}};s.parentNode.insertBefore(tk,s)
	  })(document);
	</script>
	<script>
	  (function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){
	  (i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o),
	  m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)
	  })(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');

	  ga('create', 'UA-43254394-6', 'auto');
	  ga('send', 'pageview');

	</script>
</head>
	<body class="">
		
		

    <body>
		<!--[if lt IE 8]>
            <p class="browsehappy">You are using an <strong>outdated</strong> browser. Please <a href="http://browsehappy.com/">upgrade your browser</a> to improve your experience.</p>
        <![endif]-->
    <div class="loader"></div>
<div class="spiral"></div>
<div id="page" class="page">
	<!--</header>-->
	<div class="header--top"></div>
	<div class="page__wrapper">
		<header class="header" role="banner">
			<a href="/" class="logo" id="logo">
				<span class="logo__circle">
					<span class="logo--text">A</span>
				</span>
			</a>
			<nav class="nav" role="navigation">
				<a href="/antonio/" title="About me">About</a>
				<a href="/journal" title="Journal">Journal</a>
				<a href="https://bitbucket.org/afullone" title="">Lab</a>
			</nav>
		</header>

      <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antonio Fullone</title>
    <description>Antonio Fullone. Life, food, travelling and coding.</description>
    <link>http://antoniofullone.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://antoniofullone.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 10:01:02 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 10:01:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>“Don’t let yourself go.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As expat, I am exposed to the risk of &lt;strong&gt;depression&lt;/strong&gt; more than other people. The rate of depression among expat is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelocal.es/20130320/expat-mental-health&quot;&gt;50% more&lt;/a&gt; than the general population. That’s a lot, but predictable. 
There are many extra factors for us that can increase the risk of being depressed: 
Missing the &lt;em&gt;family&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;friends&lt;/em&gt;, adapt to a different culture, &lt;em&gt;culture shock&lt;/em&gt;, learn new &lt;em&gt;language&lt;/em&gt;, deal with bureaucracy, deal with &lt;em&gt;racism&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;social life&lt;/em&gt;, weather and many many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not depressed. I am a solar and friendly person, I smile, have fun, at work and with my friends, with my family. I even manage a community on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/designers-developers/&quot;&gt;meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life has not been easy. I lost the most important person of my life, my &lt;strong&gt;dad&lt;/strong&gt;, when I was 16. It happened the same day of my birthday. I woke up that morning excited and looking for him to receive his hugs and kisses, but the only thing that I remember was people crying around me, and him, laying on the bed, dead. It took me more than 4 years to go to the cemetery to visit him, I couldn’t. It was so hard.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People kept telling me that his death on my birthday was a sign of the destiny, that I should take his place and role, but I couldn’t. He wasn’t only my father, he was my hero and I cannot be like him, you cannot be like your hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;mum&lt;/strong&gt; took care of me and my 3 sisters, she worked hard, really hard. For her there were only those 4 children to look after, nothing else. I remember her tired at home, trying to not to cry while looking at the bills, “&lt;em&gt;money are not enough, I need to find another job&lt;/em&gt;”, that’s what she was saying every time. I was learning how to make websites, trying to make a living of that, so she could stop working. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always trusted the &lt;strong&gt;web&lt;/strong&gt;, I knew it would land me a job one day, I knew that internet would become what is now, bigger and used by everyone. I started making websites when tables were still the must, and “&lt;strong&gt;webmasters&lt;/strong&gt;” were those weird figures that people would connect to everything related to the word “pc”. But I eventually got there, I made a living with that. Last year my mum stopped to work, it was one of the best day of my life, I felt useful, I felt a little bit like him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then come my nephews, I don’t have a brother neither sons, so when my first nephew was born, it was for me like I had one. I’m also his godfather, and I am proud of him. Last spring he had &lt;strong&gt;meningitis&lt;/strong&gt;, he arrived to the hospital in &lt;em&gt;very critical conditions&lt;/em&gt;, death or brain damage are common in those cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nightmare for me, away, alone. I was crying, punching walls, going mad. As soon as I could I took the first plane and went there. I saw this child in a bed. “&lt;em&gt;He’s not my Sasi&lt;/em&gt;” - as I call him - I thought. This children was so different from my little &lt;em&gt;Sasi&lt;/em&gt;, he could not even talk with me. It was hard, were hard months, for me my family and everyone around us. Luckily he survived with no major consequences. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;sister&lt;/strong&gt;, her mum, is also a very &lt;strong&gt;strong woman&lt;/strong&gt;. Her husband had also health issues, he had a rare illness and needed a liver &lt;strong&gt;transplant&lt;/strong&gt;. I stayed with her for more than one month in the hospital waiting for the transplant. She faced both issues with husband and son with an incredible strength, I don’t know where she takes it. I can only see how strong she is, how much patience and love she gives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She reminded my &lt;strong&gt;mum&lt;/strong&gt; when taking care of my dying father, they both never give up. They are strong women, women made strong by life. I wish I could be strong like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not like them. instead I suffer from &lt;em&gt;sleep disorders&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;anxiety&lt;/em&gt;. I almost never sleep well, I often wake up in the morning way too early and sometimes the “&lt;strong&gt;bitch&lt;/strong&gt;” - as I call the anxiety - comes to visit me. Often when I am alone.I had tough moments and living abroad, alone, doesn’t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all these problems I still smile, laugh, have fun with friends and nope, as I said, I am not depressed and neither close to it. &lt;strong&gt;Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt; is a common problem nowadays, it affects a large part of the population, our life style has changed. We live for work, career, &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;. We stress ourselves every day and anxiety it’s just a normal consequence of all this. I am fully aware of that and I keep living my life normally despite all the problems I might face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do when I have those moments when I “feel down” ? I &lt;strong&gt;reach for help&lt;/strong&gt;. I call someone in my family, or go to drink a beer with a good friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like you are drowning in a &lt;strong&gt;river&lt;/strong&gt;, it might be scary but if you just look around, if you just do a minimal effort to get out, you will always find your way. There is always someone ready to give you his hand and help you out. &lt;em&gt;You are never alone&lt;/em&gt;.
But if you let yourself go, then well .. the risk to be dragged in the big &lt;strong&gt;sea of depression&lt;/strong&gt; is high, and then it’s very hard to come back, to find the mainland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people in my situation would have fallen in this sea, but I didn’t. I am lucky, I have people that love me. My family is awesome, they are my &lt;em&gt;source of inspiration&lt;/em&gt;. But also every time I had problems &lt;strong&gt;I asked for help&lt;/strong&gt;, either a friend or one of my sisters, I know I am never alone and I know when I need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for many others out there is not so easy, it’s not just about writing a blog post. It was hard to take the decision to share this post, but I decided to tell my story to let you know that you are not alone in this, we all go trough issues in our lives, sometimes they seems impossible to solve it, they make you feel impotent, useless. Some of them will change your life forever like happened to me. Losing the person you love is a huge pain, I went trough this more than once. I spent days in hospital for the people I love and they would do the same for me. I cried, lost hopes, went trough a lot of bad things, but I am still here. Smiling with my friends, my colleagues, my family. I never give up, as my family Taught me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it hurts, I know it’s painful and I know you cannot make it alone. You need to ask for help, if you just look around you, I am sure you will find someone that cares about you, that will &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to you. Don’t let you drag in that sea, &lt;strong&gt;ask for help&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t let yourself go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my contribute to &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekmentalhelp.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#geekmentalhelp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; week. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 23:30:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://antoniofullone.com/life/2014/10/30/feeling-down/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://antoniofullone.com/life/2014/10/30/feeling-down/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bye Bye Wordpress, welcome Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;img--post-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jekyll.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll home page&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Jekyll is easy to install&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use to blog a couples of times for year, maybe three. Wordpress is really too much for me, I am tired of dealing with updates, database, plugins, spam. I did a first small move the last time that I redesigned my blog, making the about and home page static, and moving only to (real) blog part to Wordpress, but it turnout that was even more hard to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the template system in Wordpress is complex while I, as you can see, I like to keep this site much simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to all my questions is Jekyll. I was intrigued to use it, but a little bit “scared”,  I found out instead that is really easy to set up and use. I installed the Mac version, opened my Textmate and started moving the code from Wordpress to static pages in less than a weekend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has his own template system, and once you do the build, the only thing is to use the same name pattern for the posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why I moved to Jekyll is the fact that I love writing with IAWriter, which has a very good support for Markdown, and Jekyll uses Markdown for its posts, so it’s a perfect combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing to do was to find a good way to avoid to deploy manually every time, so I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dmathieu/glynn&quot;&gt;Glynn&lt;/a&gt; which does the job for you, deploying also on the FTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to move also my italian blog (which basically will just be a copy of this one, but probably different contents) where I use to blog more often, like 6/7 times a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very happy now with the results, here some simple advantages I found on Jekyll: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Template : as I said above, easy, simple faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Static pages mean also speed, the page now load much faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy writing with Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ridiculously easy to update and maintain. You just need a grunt file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More freedom on styling and editing the posts, I can get rid of the rigid template system and build custom post each time I want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to update. It’s just html right? :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 22:48:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://antoniofullone.com/dev/2014/10/27/bye-bye-wordpress-welcome-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://antoniofullone.com/dev/2014/10/27/bye-bye-wordpress-welcome-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
  

        </div>
</div>
<footer role="contentinfo">
	<p class="footer__contact">
		<a href="http://www.antoniofullone.it">Italian</a>
		<a href="#">Top</a>
	</p>
	<p class="footer_copyright">Antonio Fullone - &copy;2009 - 2014</p>
</footer>
<script src="/main.js"></script> 

    </body>
</html>